Daniel Williams

3847 Eglinton Avenue, Toronto, ON, CANADA | (716) 965 5365 | darkhorse0304@gmail.com

Summary Statement

Daniel is a dedicated web developer who specializes in developing full-stack web applications using practical frameworks. He's passionate about solving problems for others. A good solution to Daniel usually requires a dose of creativity that then requires more effort to adapt and perfect.

Work Experience

SENIOR FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

Kindbody, L.A, California (January 2020 - April 2022)

- · Maintained and improved the client portal React application.
- · Worked in a team of 4 and developed a new UI framework based on a styled system, TypeScript and React.
- Built an integration with a third-party identity verification solution to ensure that agents on the platform are verified and no fraudulent user accounts are created.
- · Used AWS S3 in order to handle all uploaded assets and managed hosting with AWS EC2 and route5.
- Developed of a payment, tipping, and vendor management system for an audio sharing platform using Ruby on Rails (RoR) and React.

Technologies: ROR, React, Redux, PostgreSQL, TypeScript, , AWS S3, AWS Amplify, AWS CDK, Online Payments

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

Payfirma, Vancouver, B.C, CANADA (September 2016 – June 2019)

- · Performed a security audit of the code and application.
- · Improved the UI and UX across the entire application with an overhaul of the existing CSS code.
- · Created developer tools and documentation to enhance developer workflow.
- · Mentored junior developers as needed on solving issues, code patterns, and general best practices.
- Retrofitted the entire product for multilingual support as a requirement for the advance of a major financial partnership.

Technologies: React, Redux-Saga, GraphQL, TypeScript, SCSS, Node.js, OAuth

FRONT END DEVELOPER

Myxer, Austin, Texas, U.S. (September 2014 – April 2016)

- Fixed several bugs and reworked the UI/UX to provide smoother interactions with a web app while music was streaming.
- · Developed a streaming music service front-end that allows users to create custom radio stations.
- · Developed and maintained the core SaaS solution with Ruby on Rails (RoR), MySQL, Redis, and AngularJS.
- · Developed and maintained the core ROR marketplace, React front-end, and the AWS infrastructure.

Technologies: ROR, Angular, React, JavaScript, Docker, MySQL, AWS CDK, AWS Amplify, AWS S3

Education

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (B.S.) IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

University of Victoria, Victoria, BC

September 2011- April 2014

Skills & Abilities

- · Expert: ROR, Node, JavaScript, C/C++, React, Vue, Angular, Git, SQL, Mongo, AWS, HTML/CSS, jQuery
- · Advanced: PHP, Laravel, Python, Django, Web3.js, C#, .NET, Next, Nuxt, GraphQL, Docker
- · Familiar: Java, Spring Boot, Flask, etc.

Languages

· English: Native or Bilingual Proficiency